Just like you can change the value of an integer variable after you've
整変数を作成した後に値が 変更できたように
created it, you can also change the value of a string variable.
ストリング変数の値も変更が可能です
You can update it to a completely new value.
全て新しい値に変更できます
In our Just Java app, say we wanted to display a special drink of the day.
例えば Just Java アプリで “本日の スペシャルドリンク” を表示する場合
Then we could use a string variable to store the name of that drink.
ストリング変数を利用すれば そのドリンクの名称が記憶されます
Here we declare a string variable called drinkOfTheDay and
ここでは "drinkOfTheDay" という ストリング変数で宣言します
we initially set it to the value Latte.
最初に値を "Latte" に設定します
With our box analogy this is what it would look like.
ボックスアナロジーでは この様になります
We have the Latte value stored inside this variable.
この変数の中には "Latte" という値が 記憶されています
On another line of code we can say drinkOfTheDay equals a new string value.
こちらのコードラインではイコールの右側に 新たなストリング値をおくことができます
Now the word Espresso is stored in this string.
ここでは単語 "Espresso" が 記憶されます
We don't need to specify the data type string again,
既にここでストリングとして 宣言されているため
because it was already declared as a string up here.
データ形式のストリングを再度 特定する必要はありません
On the next line of code if we say drinkOfTheDay equals Green Tea,
次のコードラインではイコールの右側に "Green Tea" とありますので
then we store Green Tea into this variable now.
この変数に "Green Tea" を 記憶させます
Here's another example where we might want to display the store hours
お店の営業時間もアプリに加えたいと 思うのでもう一つ例を
within our app.
あげましょう
We can create a string variable to store the text that
画面に表示するテキストを 記憶させるための
should be displayed on the screen.
ストリング変数の作成ができます
The initial value is Open today from 8AM to 5PM.
初期値は "Open today from 8AM to 5PM" です
On a different day we can update the string variable to say Open today from
別の日でストリング変数を "Open today from 8AM to 2PM" に
8AM to 2PM, because we want to leave early to go to the beach.
変更が可能です--早く終わってビーチに 行きたい日もありますからね
Or on another day we can update the store hours to say Closed today,
または日曜日を営業しない日にして 営業時間を "Closed today" に
because we don't work on Sundays.
変更することもできます
If our app had a running list of all the drinks that the user wanted
ユーザーが注文した全ての飲み物が このアプリにリストアップされた場合は
then we could create a string variable called drinksOrdered.
ストリング変数 "drinksOrdered" を 作成します
We could start it off with one drink, like 1 mocha.
"1 mocha" のように一つの飲み物から 始められます
In the variable we would store the text 1 mocha.
変数には "1 mocha" と記憶させます
And then if the user wants another drink,
ユーザーが飲み物をもう一つ 注文する場合は
then we can just concatenate the new drink onto the existing drinksOrdered.
既存の "drinksOrdered" に 新たな飲み物を連結するだけです
This gets stored inside the variable drinksOrdered like this.
変数 "drinksOrdered" の中に こうして記憶されます
If I want to add another drink,
さらにもう一つ飲み物を足す場合は
I can just concatenate that onto the existing string drinksOrdered.
こちらも既存の変数 "drinksOrdered" と 連結させるだけです
This expression evaluates to one long string that says 1 mocha, 1 cappuccino,
この表現式は一つの長いストリングとなり "1 mocha, 1 cappuccino, 1 macchiato"
1 macchiato.
と表示されます
All of that gets stored into this variable like this.
これら全てがこの様に 変数に記憶されます
It might look a little funny to have a comma and
ストリングの頭にコンマとスペースが あることに多少違和感を
a space at the beginning of this string,
覚えるかもしれませんが
but that just makes the list look nice with commas in between each item.
これは単にコンマが商品の間にある方が リストが見やすくなるからです
The reason why I didn't put a comma at the end of cappuccino is because
"cappuccino" の後にコンマを 入れない理由は
I can't be sure if there's going to be another drink coming after that or not.
この先さらに飲み物の注文が入るかどうか 定かでないからです
If there's only two drinks, then I will say 1 mocha,
飲み物が２つだけなら "1 mocha, 1 cappuccino" となって
1 cappuccino and that looks fine as is.
そのままで大丈夫ですが
If there's another drink coming, like a macchiato,
"macchiato" といった 追加でもう１つ飲み物がある場合は
then I can just add a comma because I know another drink is coming.
次も注文が入ると分かっているので コンマを加えるだけでいいのです
Go ahead and try this out in Android Studio.
どうぞ Android Studio で 試してみてください
Add another line of code that updates the string variable to a new value,
ストリング変数を更新する新たな値を もう１つコードラインに追加します
or you can update it to the current value plus some more stuff.
または現在の値を更新して さらに多く追加することもできます
Once you're comfortable with knowing how to update string variables in
Android Studio でストリング変数を 更新することに慣れてきましたら
Android Studio, then go ahead and
次へ進みましょう
implement this final behavior in the app for lesson two.
レッスン２ではアプリの最終操作を 実行しましょう
When you change the quantity and hit the Order button, it should say Total and
数量を変えて ORDER ボタンを押すと 表示が "Total" と
the price, and then Thank you!
"Thank you!" と出ます
Technically you don't need to update the string variable in order to build out
実際はこの機能性を増やすために ストリング変数の更新をする必要は
this functionality.
ありませんが
However, I'd still like you to do so if you can.
可能であればやって欲しいと思います
In the next lesson you're going to need to update string variables more often,
次のレッスンではストリング変数をもっと 頻繁に更新する必要性が出てきます
specifically because there's going to be more fields in this order form and
特にこの注文書において 使うフィールドが増え
we're going to need to build up the order summary.
発注明細も作ることになるからです
When you're done, check these boxes to continue.
終わりましたらこれらのボックスに チェックを入れて続きへ進みましょう
This is the last coding task of the lesson, so good luck.
レッスンでのコーディングタスクは これで終了しました--健闘を祈ります